<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://meeteliza.github.io</id>
    <title>Meet Eliza</title>
    <updated>2021-01-07T13:58:07.941Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://meeteliza.github.io"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://meeteliza.github.io/atom.xml"/>
    <subtitle>努力实现自由而全面的发展！</subtitle>
    <logo>https://meeteliza.github.io/images/avatar.png</logo>
    <icon>https://meeteliza.github.io/favicon.ico</icon>
    <rights>All rights reserved 2021, Meet Eliza</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[学习进度1.7-1.17]]></title>
        <id>https://meeteliza.github.io/post/xue-xi-jin-du-17-117/</id>
        <link href="https://meeteliza.github.io/post/xue-xi-jin-du-17-117/">
        </link>
        <updated>2021-01-07T09:33:23.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>本期需要完成一下几个任务</p>
<ul>
<li>口译journal</li>
<li>双学位论文定题
<ul>
<li>写邮件✅</li>
<li>确定</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>国际组织学期
<ul>
<li>论文、</li>
<li>proposal、</li>
<li>ppt✅</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>经济外交学期论文</li>
<li>学位论文第一次讨论
<ul>
<li>确定时间✅</li>
<li>讨论准备</li>
<li>讨论</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>东亚政治学习</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[栏目安排]]></title>
        <id>https://meeteliza.github.io/post/lan-mu-an-pai/</id>
        <link href="https://meeteliza.github.io/post/lan-mu-an-pai/">
        </link>
        <updated>2021-01-07T09:30:26.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>News briefing：一般是原封不动搬运新闻，速记能力+语言积累<br>
学习记录：任务安排、日常打卡记录</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2020 Election]]></title>
        <id>https://meeteliza.github.io/post/2020-election/</id>
        <link href="https://meeteliza.github.io/post/2020-election/">
        </link>
        <updated>2021-01-07T09:28:12.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>这一篇回顾2020美国大选经过</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[News briefing: US Congress seals Biden's election victory after chaotic day in Washington]]></title>
        <id>https://meeteliza.github.io/post/news-briefing-us-congress-seals-bidens-election-victory-after-chaotic-day-in-washington/</id>
        <link href="https://meeteliza.github.io/post/news-briefing-us-congress-seals-bidens-election-victory-after-chaotic-day-in-washington/">
        </link>
        <updated>2021-01-07T09:12:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Retrieved from Global News. Written by Sean Boynton. January 7, 2021.</p>
]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Retrieved from Global News. Written by Sean Boynton. January 7, 2021.</p>
<!-- more -->
<p>The US Congress finally affirmed President-elect Joe Biden's election victory early Thursday, after an Electoral Colledge vote count that was interrupted by both Republican objections and supporters of President Donald Trump who violently seiged the Capitol.</p>
<p>Vice-President Mike Pence declared Biden and vice-president-elect Kamala Harris the winners of November's election, <strong>putting the final nail in the coffin for Trump's hopes</strong> that the results could be overturned, either by Pence or Republican lawmakers.</p>
<p>Those hopes had helped lead supporters to storm the Capitol building Wednesday, interrupting the vote count and debates resulting from Republican efforts to strike down the results of battleground states. Four people were killed over the course of the riot, which forced lawmakers to shelter in their offices and the House chamber for hours.</p>
<pre><code class="language-bash">final nail in the coffin: An event, decision, action, etc., that seals, confirms, or ultimately leads to the failure of a situation or event that has already begun to fail.
</code></pre>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="1"><img src="https://meeteliza.github.io/post-images/1610014407033.png" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<p>Trump has spent months falsely claiming the election was stolen from him through widespread voter fraud, which has been debunked by multiple officials. He urged his supporters on Wednesday and the days before to put pressure on Republicans to mount challenges to the electoral vote.</p>
<p>With Democrats in control of the House and top Senate Republicans vocally against objecting to the vote, the efforts were doomed to failure before they begain. Biden and Harris will be inaugurated on Jan. 20.</p>
<p>In a statement released by his communications staff shortly after Pence's declaration, Trump promised there will be an orderly transition of power &quot;even though I totally disagree with the outcome of the election.&quot; &quot;While this represents the end of the greatest first term in presidential history, it's only the beginning of our fight to Make America Great Again!&quot;, the statement read.</p>
<pre><code class="language-bash">mount a challenge: to organize and initiate a challenge
</code></pre>
<h3 id="attempts-to-object-to-the-count">Attempts to object to the count</h3>
<p>Republicans had mounted an objection to Arizona's electors before protesters breached the Capitol. After police finally cleared the building, the required debate over the objection resumed.</p>
<p>Yet the chaos of the day appeared to force some Republicans to reconsider, with senators openly stating during the debate that they would no longer object to any certifications of the vote.</p>
<p>Under US law, any objection to a state's electors must be submitted by both a member of the House of Representatives and a senator. Originally, 13 Republican senators had said they would join the more than 100 House members in objecting. Once a vote was called, however, only six Senators supported the objection to Arizona's electors. All other senators voted to suspend the objection.</p>
<p>The objection also failed in the House by a margin of 303-121 on Wednesday night, with only Republicans voting in support. Once the two chambers resumed their joint session and continued counting each state's electors, it became clear that the Republican effort to object to multiple states was largely <strong>quashed</strong>.</p>
<pre><code class="language-bash">quash: reject or void, especially by legal procedure.
Arizona: 亚利桑那州
</code></pre>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="2"><img src="https://meeteliza.github.io/post-images/1610025849312.png" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<p>Despite House members' efforts, objections to the elections in Georgia, Michigan and Nevada were shot down when senators withdrew their support.</p>
<p>An objection to Pennsylvania's electors was later joined by Sen. Josh Hawley, forcing the two chambers to once again split for debate.</p>
<p>Yet Hawley said he would not give remarks after earlier speaking during the debate over Arizona. The Senate declied to debate the objection at all, leading to another defeat of the motion, this time by a <strong>margin</strong> of 92-7.</p>
<p>Senate Majority Leader Mitch McConnell said he believed no other states' votes will be challenged. But the senators still had to wait for the debate in the House to conclude, which didn't happen untill close to 3 am. The House also rejected the Pennsylvania objection.</p>
<p>A final attempt to object to the count, this time for the state of Wisconsin, was quickly defeated after an unnamed senator withdrew their support.</p>
<p>Hawley had argued in the earlier Arizona debate that he was doing his Constitutional duty by voicing concerns about election integrity, despite those concerns being based almost entirely on false and debunked claims of fraud.</p>
<p>Even before the Capitol was breached, McConnell offered a strong rebuke to the challenge, saying the country &quot;cannot keep drifting apart into two separate tribes,&quot; addng that the attempt to overturn the election results would &quot;damage the republic forever.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The voters, the courts and the states all have spoken,&quot; McConnell said.</p>
<p>Once it resumed, the debate saw many Republicans condemn their colleagues for delaying the inevitable certification of Biden's win, particularly in light of the day's events when protesters breached the Capitol. Senators traced the protester's anger directly to statements from Trump and other Republicans questioning the election's legitimacy.</p>
<pre><code class="language-bash">margin: 幅度; to lose by a small margin以微弱的差距失利
Capitol: 国会大厦; the seat of the US Congress in Washington, DC
</code></pre>
<p>While Romney has long criticized Trump and was the only Republican who voted to remove him from office after the president's impeachment, some of Trump's supporters in Congress also moved to end the debate over the election.</p>
<p>After Republicans raised objections, Republican Rep. Andy Harris and Democratic Rep. Colin Allred began to yell at each other to &quot;sit down&quot; from across the floor.</p>
<p>A confrontation in the aisle of the House floor followed, with several members of both parties clearing from the seats on their respective sides to try and break up the confrontation.</p>
<p>Biden won all the states that were subject to Republican objections, securing enough Electoral College votes to win the presidency.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DesignSeeds色卡配色]]></title>
        <id>https://meeteliza.github.io/post/pei-se/</id>
        <link href="https://meeteliza.github.io/post/pei-se/">
        </link>
        <updated>2021-01-05T10:00:35.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>前几天做视频在pinterest发现的神仙配色网站 <a href="https://www.design-seeds.com/blog/page/2/">Design Seeds</a>, 可以根据颜色大类、关键字找到喜欢的颜色。此外，运营方会定期收录优秀配色，放在Blog这条菜单下，每一条blog预览如下图。</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="1"><img src="https://meeteliza.github.io/post-images/1609841268046.png" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hexo简单教程]]></title>
        <id>https://meeteliza.github.io/post/hexo-instruction/</id>
        <link href="https://meeteliza.github.io/post/hexo-instruction/">
        </link>
        <updated>2021-01-05T09:49:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>以下都是用visual studio code写出来的，这里存档一下以前的尝试，就不修改了。</p>
]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>以下都是用visual studio code写出来的，这里存档一下以前的尝试，就不修改了。</p>
<!-- more -->
<p>title: Hexo Instruction<br>
date: 2020-11-12 21:56:44<br>
tags: Instructions<br>
This article only deals with how to handle daily operation like creating a new blog, managing the homepage, and uploading the static page onto Github. More information click <a href="https://youtu.be/e41xmS3KAG0">installation</a> or <a href="https://youtu.be/tEFKJeAtGqk">operation</a>.</p>
<h3 id="open-the-local-website">Open the local website</h3>
<p>Open Terminal, and type in:</p>
<pre><code class="language-bash">$ cd desktop
</code></pre>
<p>Depending on where you keep your files, it could be [desktop], [download], [document] or the like.</p>
<pre><code class="language-bash">$ cd MyFirstHexoBlog
</code></pre>
<p>These two steps are to locate the file where your website is saved. [MyFirstHexoBlog] is the name I give to the folder where I keep my website file. Be sure to change it to yours when following the instructions.</p>
<pre><code class="language-bash">$ hexo server
</code></pre>
<p>So now you can copy the link generated by Terminal and paste it on a Browser to see your website.</p>
<h3 id="create-a-new-blog">Create a new Blog</h3>
<pre><code class="language-bash">$ hexo new &quot;My New Post&quot;
</code></pre>
<p>Once this step is done, a new file is automatically created into the original folder, and now your can write your blog with the help of Visual Studio Code. Go to [source/posts] and it's the item that ends with [.md]. Remember to keep one original file for reference.</p>
<h3 id="install-a-theme">Install a theme</h3>
<p>Go to <a href="https://hexo.io/">Hexo official website</a> and look for a theme you like. Once you find a proper one, go to its Github page and copy its URL. Open Terminal and type in:</p>
<pre><code class="language-bash">$ git clone https://**** themes/themename
</code></pre>
<p>Then it's downloading the theme to your website folder, and saving it under [theme] by the name of [themename] or other name you prefer. Once it's downloaded, go to Visial Studio Code, open [config.yml] under the themes folder, locate the line related with theme name and change it to the new one. Restart the server once finished.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gridea网页记录]]></title>
        <id>https://meeteliza.github.io/post/kai-zhan-ji-lu/</id>
        <link href="https://meeteliza.github.io/post/kai-zhan-ji-lu/">
        </link>
        <updated>2021-01-05T08:34:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>关于最初的尝试，和网页内容的构想</p>
]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>关于最初的尝试，和网页内容的构想</p>
<!-- more -->
<p>去年六月份开始学创建个人网站，下半年因为要准备考研所以暂时搁置了。github pages + hexo这一条路对没有编程基础的人实在不太友好，因为不理解git是怎么运作的，第一次用hexo建好本地网站，链接到github上之后，九月份我想更新一下，就又得从零开始，git init、hexo server、hexo g都按教程做好了，但是本地到漫游这一步又不知道哪里出了问题。今天本来打算删掉之前的仓库，重新从零开始再搭一遍，幸好偶然发现了gridea～，再也不用打开终端了～</p>
<p>目前的想法是写写总结，比如我喜欢乱开一些新坑，不记录的话下一次就又得从头捡起。然后还可以写议论文，我一开始就是想为考研训练自己议论文写作来着，网上找的观点，要么是用于debate的，比较口语化，要么是观点跟当前环境脱节，而且我也没办法采用我自己不赞同的观点，就想说可以自己写，或者整理一些我认可的观点，做成一个可读性比较强coherent的文章。还比较想做的就是专业学科mind map的搭建。很多课都挺有意思的，但是往往学过就忘了，笔记本找起来也麻烦，但是写在网站上就不同了，自己还会经常翻一翻，便于查阅。当然也不限于自己的专业学科，一些common knowledge也同理。</p>
<p>2021年1月5日先更到这，我去把上次hexo写的总结搬过来，开始愉快布置自己的网站，加油⛽️</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
</feed>